### Raza Tahir

Razat51@gmail.com | (818) 916-3621 | North Hollywood, CA www.itsraza.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate and passionate programmer with over two years of responsible experience in website design and application development and possesses reading and interpreting technical documentation skills, excellent cooperative, creative and organizational skills, and proficient in application software and office software.

#### **SKILLS**

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, XML, Bootstrap, jQuery, ASP.NET Core

Tools: Microsoft Office 365, Adobe Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, WordPress

**Operating Systems:** Windows 10, Mac OSX

Soft Skills: Web Design, SEO, Responsive Design, Video Editing, Social Media

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

AutoManager Web Support Analyst Canoga Park, CA

Mar 2019 – Present

AutoManager provides software and web development services to car dealerships. I am responsible for web design and refining SEO (search engine optimization) strategies.

- Reduced incident resolution time by ~50% by tracking and monitoring web design related incidents and problems
- Documented issues and product enhancements to ensure awareness of potential bugs in the software system.
- Improved search rankings for 150 car dealer websites by analyzing websites, refining SEO strategies and providing data-driven recommendations on performance and visibility.
- Saved 10 minutes per customer in lead generation activities by automating follow up and documentation process using Python program scripts.

## Rahbar Travel .NET Application Developer Intern

Los Angeles, CA

January 2018 - Dec 2018

Rahbar Travel is a travel startup that aims to deliver spiritual, comfortable, and enduring Hajj and Umrah experiences for Muslims around the world. I was responsible for developing a cross-browser compatible scalable web application.

- Improved lead conversion by developing and launching new front-end design, UX design and translating wireframes and mockups into interactive live pages.
- Reduced time spent by the team on content changes by 40% by developing and implementing reusable components; helped deliver consistent design throughout the site.
- Participated in daily Scrum meetings to discuss how to add on, improve, or debug the existing website.
- Created test cases and analyzed 40 features for each case manually on multiple devices to spot functionality issues early in the product life cycle.

# One Step Learning Center Coding Instructor

Los Angeles, CA May 2017 - Dec 2017

• Utilized knowledge and skills in C++ to educate 20 children the essentials of computer programming.

#### **EDUCATION**

California State University, Fullerton Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Fullerton, CA 2016 – 2018